

+41766389833yz-cnsdqz.github.io/5VpkLO8AAAAJ

in yan-zhang-3119b11a☑ yan.zhang@inf.ethz.ch♀ yz-cnsdqz

Professional Summary

I am a postdoc researcher at ETH Zurich for 3 years, and have been studying on digital human technologies. My researches cover human body/motion modeling, generative models, body pose estimation and motion capture, etc, as well as their applications in mixed reality, architecture design, and healthcare.

Publications (selective)

Zhang, Yan, and Siyu Tang. "The Wanderings of Odysseus in 3D Scenes." CVPR 2022.

Zhang, Yan, Michael J. Black, and Siyu Tang. "We are more than our joints: Predicting how 3d bodies move." CVPR 2021.

Zhang, Yan, Mohamed Hassan, Heiko Neumann, Michael J. Black, and Siyu Tang. "Generating 3d people in scenes without people." CVPR 2020 **Oral**.

Zhang, Yan, Siyu Tang, Krikamol Muandet, Christian Jarvers, Heiko Neumann. "Local temporal bilinear pooling for fine-grained action parsing." CVPR 2019.

Zhang, Yan, Siyu Tang, He Sun, Heiko Neumann. "Human Motion Parsing by Hierarchical Dynamic Clustering." BMVC 2018.

Zhang, Siwei, Qianli Ma, **Yan Zhang**, Zhiyin Qian, Taein Kwon, Marc Pollefeys, Federica Bogo, Siyu Tang. "Egobody: Human body shape and motion of interacting people from head-mounted devices." ECCV 2022.

Zhang, Siwei, **Yan Zhang**, Federica Bogo, Marc Pollefeys, and Siyu Tang. "Learning motion priors for 4d human body capture in 3d scenes." ICCV 2021 **Oral**.

Zhao, Kaifeng, Shaofei Wang, **Yan Zhang**, Thabo Beeler, and Siyu Tang. "Compositional Human-Scene Interaction Synthesis with Semantic Control." ECCV 2022.

Korrawe Karunratanakul, Jinlong Yang, **Yan Zhang**, Michael J Black, Krikamol Muandet, Siyu Tang. "Grasping field: Learning implicit representations for human grasps." 3DV 2020 **Best Paper Award**

Awards and Service

3DV Best Paper Award

Max Planck ETH Center for Learning Systems

Review

Area Chair of 3DV'24, SIGGRAPH Asia'23, CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, TPAMI, 3DV, etc.

Organizer

Grasping field: Learning implicit representations for human grasps 2020

Associated Postdoc 2021-now

Area Chair of 3DV'24, SIGGRAPH Asia'23, CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, TPAMI, 3DV, etc.

Multi-view Cameras

Projects (selective)

Inhabiting the virtual, Flight Assembled Architecture Revisited

ETH Zurich

2022

2021-now

- Has been featured at the home page of ETH Zurich.
- Collaboration with Gramazio Kohler Research, architecture department of ETH Zurich.
- A vertical digital city is populated by intelligent digital humans wandering autonomously.
- Developed an system based on Nvidia Omniverse, which synthesizes human motions online.
- Real exhibition in Guggenheim Museum Bilbao, 2021-2023
- As a byproduct, a paper "The Wanderings of Odysseus in 3D Scenes" has been published at CVPR 2022.
- As a byproduct, a Hololens 2-based software is developed to place virtual humans in motion into the ETH main building.
- MY ROLE: project leader at the computer science department side.

Interaction Capture for Mixed Reality

ETH Zurich

2021-now

- Capturing human-human interactions and human-scene interactions based on multiview RGBD sensors and Microsoft Hololens
- Funded by Microsoft Swiss Joint Research Center
- An egocentric interaction capture dataset EgoBody has been created.
- MY ROLE: advisor and collaborator

SenseEmotionUlm University

2015-2018

- Pain recognition, behavior understanding, face analysis, etc. for elderly people healthcare.
- Funded by Federal Ministry of Education and Research, Germany, and collaborated with University Hospital Ulm and University of Augsburg, Germany.
- Multimodal capture system including cameras, audio and physiological sensors was developed, and pilot study was performed at the clinic.
- MY ROLE: responsible for research and development on behavior understanding systems and algorithms.

Technical skills

Coding and Software PyTorch, Python, C++/CUDA, Blender, Unity, Nvidia Omniverse

Education

Ph.D (Dr.rer.nat.) in Computer Science

Dec 2015 – July 2020

University of Ulm, Germany

Dissertation: Human Action Parsing in Untrimmed Videos and its Applications for Elderly People Healthcare

Grade: Sehr gut (magna cum laude).

Computer Science Graduate School

Apl 2011 – Dec. 2015

Saarland University, Germany

Grade: 1.6

M.Sc in Electronic Engineering

Sep. 2009 - Nov. 2010

University of Manchester, UK

Advanced Control and System Engineering

Grade: distinction

B.Eng in Mechanical Engineering

Sep. 2005 - Jul. 2009

Southwest Jiaotong University, China

Mechanical Design, Manufacturing, and Automation

Grade: 85%

Work Experience

ETH Zurich Visiting Researcher (6 months) and then Postdoc Researcher	2020.01 – Present Zurich, Switzerland
Max-Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems Research Assistant Intern	2018.10 – 2020.01 Tuebingen, Germany
Ulm University Research Assistant	2015.12 – 2018.09 Ulm, Germany
German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) Research Assistant Intern	2015.03 – 2015.11 Heidelberg, Germany
Saarland University Research Assistant	2012.12 – 2015.02 Saarbrucken, Germany